xtend-life.com 2018-09-06

# Privacy Policy | Xtend-Life Natural Certified Privacy

## Xtend-Life has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy.

_Effective Date: May 24, 2018_

If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us by phone on +64 3 384 2116, by email at customer.service@xtend-life.com, or by mail at PO Box 19640, Woolston, Christchurch 8241, New Zealand.

The following discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices by Xtend-Life Natural Products (Intl) Limited for this Web site: (https://www.xtend-life.com).

### Personal Information We Collect

To register for an account, we will ask for your name and email address. When you make a purchase from our website we will collect the following additional personal information: Your postal address information and credit card details. Optionally we may collect your phone number(s).

When subscribing to one of our mailing lists we will collect your name and your email address.

### How We Use Your Personal Information

If you only subscribe to our newsletter, we will only use your information to send you newsletters. No other promotional material will be sent to you based on your newsletter subscription.

When you provide us with personal information, we will use it to process and ship your order, or alternately to send you newsletter(s) to which you subscribe.

Information you provide to us will also enable you to use services we may provide through our website, including enabling you to join our membership program, and allow us to process any transactions you initiate.

When you provide us with personal information, this provides us with permission to use that information solely to provide the products and services that you have requested or purchased from us.

It will also help us communicate with you, based on your preferences, our latest news or special offers that might provide you with added value.

We do not disclose personal information to any third party apart from those directly involved in the shipping of your order.

We use a third party to send our email newsletters and only provide them with your name and your email address. No other personal details are shared with this party.

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. We do not share, sell or rent your personal information to third parties.

### Access To Personal Information

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update or delete/deactivate your account by making the change on your 'My Account' page or by emailing our Customer Support at [customer.service@xtend-life.com](mailto:customer.service@xtend-life.com) or using our [contact form.](http://help.xtend-life.com/app/ask) We aim to respond to your request to update your personal information within three business days.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you with service. If you have previously purchased a product from Xtend-Life, we will retain your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, and resolve any disputes that may arise and provide you with service.

### Service Providers

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as shipping your order or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

We use other third parties such as shipping companies to fulfil orders, a credit card processor to bill you for goods and services, and an email service provider to send out email newsletters and promotions on our behalf.

We also use a Live Chat system to assist you if you have questions while using our site(s) or enquiring about an order.

When you make a purchase from an Xtend-Life site, subscribe to a newsletter or use the Live Chat system, we will share your personal information only as necessary for the third party to provide that service.

### Information Automatically Logged

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

### Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personal information you submit while on our site.

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser's "help".

We set a persistent cookie to store your password, so you don't have to enter it every time you login. Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.

The Persistent cookie is also used to identify how you arrived at our website. This is because we have a network of affiliates and we rely on cookies to ensure that affiliates are given credit for visitors when applicable. This information is not made part of any file. We do not compile any profile of visitors to our website.

If you reject cookies, the site should still function correctly, but you may have problems with adding multiple products to our shopping cart or be able to log into your account.

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Xtend-Life Natural Products (Intl) Limited and our partners [marketing partners], affiliates, or analytics or service providers [ online customer support provider]. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 and Flash LSO to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML 5 or Flash to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To manage Flash LSOs please [click here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html).

### Behavioral Targeting/Re-targeting

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third-party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by [clicking here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.  
As you browse this website, advertising cookies will be placed on your computer so that we can understand what you are interested in. Our display advertising partner, Google Remarketing, then enables us to present you with retargeting advertising on other sites based on your previous interaction with this website. The techniques our partners employ do not collect personal information such as your name, email address, postal address or telephone number. You can visit this page to opt out of Google Remarketing and their partners' targeted advertising.

### Links To Other Sites

This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Xtend-Life Natural Products (Intl) Limited. Please be aware that we, Xtend-Life Natural Products (Intl) Limited, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personal information. This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this Web site.

### Testimonials And Product Reviews

We post customer testimonials and reviews on our web site which may contain personal information. We do obtain the customer's consent prior to posting the testimonial or review to post their first name and first letter of their last name along with their testimonial or review. If you would like to request to have your testimonial or review be removed you may contact us at [customer.service@xtend-life.com](mailto:customer.service@xtend-life.com) or by using our [contact form](http://www.xtend-life.com/Contact.aspx).

### Public Forums/Blog

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs where visitors may place comments. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog comments history, contact us at [customer.service@xtend-life.com](mailto:customer.service@xtend-life.com).

### Social Media Features and Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### Newsletter Form

When you register for our newsletter we require only your name and your email address. This detail is never released to any third party other than as outlined in this privacy policy. If your email 'bounces' or is 'full' we automatically delete your subscription. Deleted subscriptions are erased from our database. Subscribers can opt out of their subscription at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions included in each email they receive, and their requests are always honored promptly.

Information collected for the Newsletter is used to send newsletters only and no other promotional material will be sent based on your subscription.

### Loyalty Program

When you register for our Loyalty/Membership Program you will be automatically signed up for a newsletter with special Loyalty/Membership Program offers, discounts and information. For this we only require your email address. This detail is never released to any third party other than as outlined in this privacy policy. If your email 'bounces' or is 'full' we automatically delete your subscription. Deleted subscriptions are erased from our database for up to four years. Loyalty/Membership Program subscribers can opt out of their subscription at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions included in each email they receive, and their requests are always honored promptly.

### Service-related Announcements

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email.

Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account.

### Legal Disclaimer

We reserve the right to disclose your personal information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, bankruptcy proceedings or legal process served on our Web site or to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

### Business Transitions

In the event Xtend-Life Natural Products Limited goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personal information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email or prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

### PayPal

When using PayPal, we do not store PayPal credentials. However, customers who wish to pay for their orders using PayPal are still required to enter their delivery address and contact information in order for us to process the purchase.

### Security

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

We use [Qualys](https://www.qualys.com/) to ensure the security and privacy of our on-line systems, and follow industry best practice in the maintenance and monitoring of security updates, while using multiple vendors to protect our systems from vulnerabilities and malicious software. Our site uses secure encrypted forms for customers to place their product orders. Through these secure forms we collect contact information, shipping details and credit card info. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at [customer.service@xtend-life.com](mailto:customer.service@xtend-life.com) or via our [contact form](http://help.xtend-life.com/app/ask).

### Changes To This Privacy Policy

We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

### Questions

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with us please either telephone us toll free on 1 888 487 9304 if in the US or Canada or, (64) 3 384 2116 if in another country. Or alternatively [contact us here](http://help.xtend-life.com/app/ask) or via postal mail at PO Box 19640, Woolston, Christchurch 8241, New Zealand.
